<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>fritzm.github.io</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://fritzm.github.io/</id><updated>2015-07-03T14:56:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>PDP-11/45: CPU Backplane and logic</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/backplane-and-logic.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-03T14:56:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Fritz Mueller</name></author><id>tag:fritzm.github.io,2015-07-03:backplane-and-logic.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mounted the CPU backplane, and slotted in the CPU and MMU logic cards.  The empty slots on the right are for the FPU -- I have those on hand but figure I'll wait to slot them until I've got the basic CPU up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One kind of interesting thing: the logic boards were stored vertically for several decades, and on some of the cards with plastic ribbon-cable connectors the plastic seems to have flaked and shed and fallen down the boards.  The flakey substance then grew some impressive crystals between some of the solder traces.  Scrubbed these out with some anhydrous IPA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tip I copied from a fellow restorer is to use Alconox detergent for removing grime from various plastic components.  Parts soaked overnight come out looking nearly new (here you can see the cleaned plastic card guides).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also pictured here are the characteristic bloody knuckles that are obtained whenever wrestling with PDP backplanes, logic cards, and terminators in close confines.  That really takes you back...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/boards-in-chassis.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/boards-in-chassis.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/board-with-crystals.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/board-with-crystals.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/crystals.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/crystals.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/knuckles.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/knuckles.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Retro-Computing"></category><category term="PDP-11"></category></entry><entry><title>PDP-11/45: H742s and front panel</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/panel-and-742s.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-21T18:14:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Fritz Mueller</name></author><id>tag:fritzm.github.io,2015-06-21:panel-and-742s.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The H742 supplies are now back together, mounted in the cabinet, and wired through to the 861.  I've powered them up and run them for minutes at a time (without any DC regulator loads) and there have been no surprise detonations...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The repainted cabinet side door has also been remounted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spent some time on the front panel as well.  Removed the tubular lock and took a trip to the local locksmith to have a new key made up.  Replaced all the incandescent indicator lamps with the closest modern equivalent.  Panel is now remounted and it's starting to look like a real '11!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/742s-mounted.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/742s-mounted.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/front-panel.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/front-panel.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Retro-Computing"></category><category term="PDP-11"></category></entry><entry><title>PDP-11/45: AC power and cooling</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/fans-and-h742s.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-07T14:15:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Fritz Mueller</name></author><id>tag:fritzm.github.io,2015-06-07:fans-and-h742s.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Spent a lot of time over a couple weekends cleaning and reconditioning all the muffin cooling fans for the CPU cabinet and power supplies.  As you can see in the photo below, there are a lot of these!  All reassembled now, and wired along with the back-of-cabinet power distribution board.  Also did a clean on the big box fan at the top of the rack, not seen here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also completely torn down the H742s to give them a thorough clean, touch up a few last corrosion spots, and replace the failing neon indicators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/chassis-with-fans.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/chassis-with-fans.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/742-rebuild.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/742-rebuild.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Retro-Computing"></category><category term="PDP-11"></category></entry><entry><title>PDP-11/45: H742 power control boards</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/power-controllers.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-23T16:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Fritz Mueller</name></author><id>tag:fritzm.github.io,2015-05-23:power-controllers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Found a little time to clean up and go through the power control boards for the H742 supplies.  They are looking pretty good.  Even the big electrolytics seem fine on first look.  These things were built with very high quality components, and they really seem to last and last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/pwr-ctrls.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/pwr-ctrls.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Retro-Computing"></category><category term="PDP-11"></category></entry><entry><title>PDP-11/45: Teardown and corrosion remediation</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/corrosion.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-11T18:45:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Fritz Mueller</name></author><id>tag:fritzm.github.io,2015-04-11:corrosion.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Had a little more time to work on the PDP-11 this weekend.  Mostly going after some corrosion on the CPU cabinet and H742 power supplies.  Tore these down, sanded down the corroded bits, then hit with a satin finish Rustoleum rattle-can which dries to a reasonable approximation of the original powder-coat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neon indicators on the H742s are dim and flickery, so ordered some replacements for these, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/h742-teardown.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/h742-teardown.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/h742-corrosion.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/h742-corrosion.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/cpu-cabinet.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/cpu-cabinet.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Retro-Computing"></category><category term="PDP-11"></category></entry><entry><title>PDP-11/45: 861 AC power control</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/861.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-29T10:35:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Fritz Mueller</name></author><id>tag:fritzm.github.io,2015-03-29:861.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, might as well start at the beginning with the AC power system, so here's the 861 power control.  In very good shape for some 40 year old kit!  The neon indicator lamps have gone, so I sourced the modern equivalent and put them on order.  Everything else is tight and clean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/861.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/861.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Retro-Computing"></category><category term="PDP-11"></category></entry><entry><title>PDP-11/45: Begin Again</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/begin-again.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-15T18:45:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Fritz Mueller</name></author><id>tag:fritzm.github.io,2015-03-15:begin-again.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[TL;DR: Ancient history of a PDP-11/45 that I've had for years, and have now begun to restore in earnest. Pics at the bottom!]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, sometime back in the mid/late '80s, I was an undergraduate at CMU.  This was just at a time when the older DEC and IBM timesharing systems on campus, with their clusters of attached serial terminals, were on their way out.  The replacements were clusters of IBM PCs and RTs, Sun workstations, and toaster Macs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point, a CMU computer club member introduced me to the club's nearly forgotten hardware lab (basement of Baker Hall I think), still stuffed with remnants of the earlier age.  This included two or three full-cabinet PDP-11 systems with names like "Banshee" and "Centaur".  I thought these were the coolest things ever -- CPUs you could see inside, and actually hack with a soldering iron and a wire wrap gun!  Real front panels with lights and toggles, and machine language programming as a physical activity.  For a kid fascinated with computers, it was great.  You couldn't get closer to the metal; you could quite literally get your head inside these machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began spending off hours in the club lab, puttering with the 11s and getting to know them.  Eventually, some of the club leadership decided it was time to clean house and remove all of the older equipment.  Most stuff was scheduled to be hauled away to the dump.  I was welcome to anything I wanted to haul away myself in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I bothered some friends with a car, disassembled one of the 11/45s there ("Banshee" I believe) which seemed like the nicest thing, and hauled it off to my off-campus house.  There it resided in the basement with many other oddments for some years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I ended up moving out to CA, and after some time the 11/45 was disassembled and packed into moving boxes for the west coast as practically as possible, leaving its beautiful but bulky cabinets behind...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of years in CA, I happened on a decomissioned two-rack 11/40 system at Stanford, essentially free for the effort of hauling.  Just the thing for reconstructing the 11/45!  So I procurred this and added it to a growing west coast equipment stash.  And then real-life set in -- job changes, house moves, raising a kid...  Through all of that I held on to the parts of these machines, vowing to "get to it someday".  I would pick at it from time to time through the years, but never had the time to really get very far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, "someday" is here!  The kid is off to college and I've moved house once again, but this time I reserved some working space for the project and pulled all the parts so they are together and accessible.  So here we go...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a some pics from the first weekend: the two H960 racks that are the bones of the whole thing, some glamour shots of the processor backplane and the RK11-C disk controller, and my buddy Chris helping to remount the RK05 drives on their rails temporarily to keep them off the floor and out of harm's way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/racks.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/racks.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/kb11a-backplane.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/kb11a-backplane.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/rk11c.jpg"&gt;&lt;img class="image-process-thumb" src="/images/pdp11/derivatives/thumb/rk11c.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://fritzm.github.io/images/pdp11/rk05-help.png"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/pdp11/rk05-help.png"/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Retro-Computing"></category><category term="PDP-11"></category></entry><entry><title>three.js and JSFiddle</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/jsfiddle-test.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-02T20:08:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Fritz Mueller</name></author><id>tag:fritzm.github.io,2014-12-02:jsfiddle-test.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a small web toy, as a test of embedding a client-side visualisation in this blog.  The toy written in JavaScript using the &lt;a href="http://threejs.org/"&gt;Three.js&lt;/a&gt; 3D graphics library, and is hosted at JSFiddle.net.  If you click the "Edit in JSFiddle" link, you'll go off site to a full multi-pane view of the toy, where you can inspect and modify and play with the various parts of the HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center"&gt;
&lt;iframe width="501" height="340" src="http://jsfiddle.net/fritzm/5cyVe/embedded/result/#result" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="Three.js"></category><category term="JSFiddle"></category></entry><entry><title>Moebious transformation animated GIFs</title><link href="http://fritzm.github.io/moebius.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-01T12:45:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Fritz Mueller</name></author><id>tag:fritzm.github.io,2014-12-01:moebius.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are some animated GIFs that I created a few years ago with MATLAB.  These characterize the action of the four classes of Moebius transformations, mapping the complex plane to itself.  They were inspired by the illustrations and analysis in a section of Tristan Needham's excellent book &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?vid=ISBN0198534469"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visual Complex Analysis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="/images/moebius/elliptic.gif"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;elliptic&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="/images/moebius/hyperbolic.gif"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;hyperbolic&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="/images/moebius/loxodromic.gif"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;loxodromic&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="/images/moebius/parabolic.gif"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;parabolic&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what's it all about?  A Moebius transformation is a mapping on the complex numbers of the form &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ M(z) = \frac{az + b}{cz + d}, $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; where &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(a, b, c, d\)&lt;/span&gt; are complex constants.  Moebius tranformations have many nice features: they are one-to-one and onto on the complex plane (extended with the addition of the "point at &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\infty\)&lt;/span&gt;"), they form a group under composition, they are conformal (angle preserving).  Interestingly, though conformality only implies that they map infinitesimal circles to other infinitesimal circles, Moebius transformations actually map circles of &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; size in the complex plane to other circles in the plane.  For a really nice exposition and proofs of these qualities, see Needham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed points on the plane under a Moebius transform will simply be solutions of &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ z = \frac{az+b}{cz+d}, $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; which is just quadratic in &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(z\)&lt;/span&gt;.  So a (non-identity) Moebius transform will have at most two fixed points, or one when there is a repeated root.  Following Needham, for the remainder of this discussion we'll refer to the fixed points of a given Moebius transformation as &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\xi_+\)&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\xi_-\)&lt;/span&gt; in the two root case, or just &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\xi\)&lt;/span&gt; in the repeated root case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the qualities above are readily observable in the animations: one or two fixed points, circles mapping to circles, one-to-one, easy to imagine extension to the whole plane.  Conformality is a little harder to see, but if you look closely you can see that the angles at each of the corners in these crazed checkerboards always remain 90°.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The GIFs were generated using a transform method.  Given a Moebius transformation with two fixed points (we will revisit the single fixed point case shortly), consider the additional Moebius transformation defined by &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ F(z) =  \frac{z - \xi_+}{z - \xi_-}. $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This will send &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\xi_+\)&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(0\)&lt;/span&gt;, and  &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\xi_-\)&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\infty\)&lt;/span&gt;.  We can now construct &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ \widetilde{M} = F \circ  M \circ F^{-1}, $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; which is itself a Moebius transformation (since the  Moebius transformations are a group under composition) and which will  have fixed points at &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(0\)&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\infty\)&lt;/span&gt;.  We can consider &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(M\)&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/span&gt; to be a transform pair; for any &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(M\)&lt;/span&gt; there is a corresponding &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/span&gt; with fixed points at &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(0\)&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\infty\)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it turns out that Moebius transformations with fixed points at both &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(0\)&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\infty\)&lt;/span&gt; reduce to a particularly simple form — that of a single complex multiplication, i.e. just a dilation and/or rotation about the origin of the complex plane.  See Needham for exposition of this.  The elliptic, hyperbolic, and loxodromic classes of Moebius transformations turn out to be those whose corresponding &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/span&gt; is a pure rotation, pure dilation, or general combination of the two, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To generate these GIFs, we decorate the complex plane on the &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/span&gt; side like a circular checkerboard or dart board, and represent the action of a given class of &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/span&gt; transformations by rotating it, dilating it, or a combination of both, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="/images/moebius/pre-elliptic.gif"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;elliptic \(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="/images/moebius/pre-hyperbolic.gif"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;hyperbolic \(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(M\)&lt;/span&gt; side, we can pick fixed points &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\xi_+\)&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\xi_-\)&lt;/span&gt; wherever we like, and then derive the corresponding &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(F\)&lt;/span&gt; as above.  For each frame, we take each point on the &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(M\)&lt;/span&gt; side, map it through &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(F\)&lt;/span&gt; to find the corresponding point on the &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/span&gt; side, and check that against a dynamic checkerboard model to see if the point should be black or white in this frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning to the repeated root, single fixed point case: we treat this similarly, but set &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="math"&gt;$$ F = \frac{1}{z - \xi}, $$&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; which sends &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\xi\)&lt;/span&gt; to &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\infty\)&lt;/span&gt;.  As before, it turns out that Moebius transformations of this form (repeated fixed point at &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\infty\)&lt;/span&gt;) reduce to a very simple form: this time, a pure translation.  The parabolic class of Moebius transformations are those whose corresponding &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/span&gt; transformation is a pure translation.  To illustrate these, we use a translating dynamic checkerboard on the &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/span&gt; side that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="/images/moebius/pre-parabolic.gif"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;parabolic \(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this can be done quite succinctly in MATLAB, once it is understood what needs to be done.  Below is the MATLAB snippet which was used to generate these GIFs.  Commenting and uncommenting various lines chooses different &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(F\)&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\widetilde{M}\)&lt;/span&gt; side checkerboard models, resulting in the different outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few lines create a 512x512 matrix of complex numbers, ranging from -3 to 3 on both the real and imaginary axes, to represent a portion of the complex plane.  This is then pre-mapped through an appropriate &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(F\)&lt;/span&gt;.  The &lt;code&gt;for&lt;/code&gt; loop iterates on each frame.  The dynamic checkerboard result is calculated as the &lt;code&gt;xor&lt;/code&gt; of various versions of functions &lt;code&gt;g1&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;g2&lt;/code&gt; operating over the premapped points.  Each frame is downsampled and written to disk as a separate file, then at the end all the frames are stitched into a movie.  I must then have used some non-matlab utility to convert the movies to animated GIFs, but I'm not sure what that was...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;512&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;512&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;ones&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)),:);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;complex&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;%Z = 1 ./ Z;        % one finite fixed point&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;./&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class="c"&gt;% two finite fixed points&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;im&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[];&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;g1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[];&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;g2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[];&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;frame&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;g1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;mod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;abs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;lt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;           &lt;span class="c"&gt;% radial, static&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;%    g1 = mod(log(abs(Z))*4+(frame-1)/15,2)&amp;lt;1; % radial, dynamic&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;%    g1 = mod(real(Z)+(frame-1)*.8/30,.8)&amp;lt;.4;  % vertical, dynamic&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;%    g2 = mod(angle(Z), pi/6)&amp;lt;(pi/12);         % circumferential, static&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;g2&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;mod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;angle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Z&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;frame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;pi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;180&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;pi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;pi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="c"&gt;% circumferential, dynamic&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;%    g2 = mod(imag(Z),.8)&amp;lt;.4;                  % horizontal, static&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;im&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(:,:,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;frame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;imresize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;xor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;g1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;g2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;bilinear&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;imwrite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;im&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(:,:,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;frame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;sprintf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;#39;frame%.2d.bmp&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;frame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;mov&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;immovie&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;255&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;im&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;gray&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;255&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;movie&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;mov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;if (!document.getElementById('mathjaxscript_pelican_#%@#$@#')) {
    var mathjaxscript = document.createElement('script');
    mathjaxscript.id = 'mathjaxscript_pelican_#%@#$@#';
    mathjaxscript.type = 'text/javascript';
    mathjaxscript.src = '//cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML';
    mathjaxscript[(window.opera ? "innerHTML" : "text")] =
        "MathJax.Hub.Config({" +
        "    config: ['MMLorHTML.js']," +
        "    TeX: { extensions: ['AMSmath.js','AMSsymbols.js','noErrors.js','noUndefined.js'], equationNumbers: { autoNumber: 'AMS' } }," +
        "    jax: ['input/TeX','input/MathML','output/HTML-CSS']," +
        "    extensions: ['tex2jax.js','mml2jax.js','MathMenu.js','MathZoom.js']," +
        "    displayAlign: 'center'," +
        "    displayIndent: '0em'," +
        "    showMathMenu: true," +
        "    tex2jax: { " +
        "        inlineMath: [ ['\\\\(','\\\\)'] ], " +
        "        displayMath: [ ['$$','$$'] ]," +
        "        processEscapes: true," +
        "        preview: 'TeX'," +
        "    }, " +
        "    'HTML-CSS': { " +
        "        styles: { '.MathJax_Display, .MathJax .mo, .MathJax .mi, .MathJax .mn': {color: 'black ! important'} }" +
        "    } " +
        "}); ";
    (document.body || document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0]).appendChild(mathjaxscript);
}
&lt;/script&gt;</summary><category term="complex analysis"></category><category term="MATLAB"></category><category term="Moebius transformations"></category><category term="Visual Complex Analysis"></category></entry></feed>